<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hugo on Nishimiya</title><link>https://blog.nishimiya.my.id/tags/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in Hugo on Nishimiya</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 06:47:37 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.nishimiya.my.id/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Switching To Hugo!</title><link>https://blog.nishimiya.my.id/post/switch-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 05:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nishimiya.my.id/post/switch-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://blog.nishimiya.my.id/post/switch-hugo/1.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Switching To Hugo!" />&lt;div class="video-wrapper">
&lt;iframe loading="lazy"
src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M_DPRIoaqyI"
allowfullscreen
title="YouTube Video"
>
&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>As of Saturday, November 2, 2024, I have officially embraced Hugo as my
go-to static website generator. My journey with Hugo all started after
catching one of Cyan Nyan&amp;rsquo;s streams, where they introduced this powerful
tool in such a way that I knew I had to try it myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previously, I built my websites by hand, using vanilla HTML and CSS. It
was a rewarding process, but it often became tedious when trying to add
new content or make updates consistently. Hugo simplifies this with
a streamlined setup that includes templating, modular design, and built-in
site management tools, making it an ideal choice for a faster, more
scalable website-building process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the game-changers for me was discovering the &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/CaiJimmy/hugo-theme-stack-starter" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>CaiJimmy Hugo Theme
Starter&lt;/a>. This theme
provides a well-structured, customizable foundation that not only speeds
up the setup process but also allows me to personalize the site with SCSS
and shortcodes. Shortcodes are especially useful—they allow you to embed
interactive content like YouTube videos effortlessly (like the one above),
as well as easily create more complex layouts within Markdown files. This
feature alone takes a lot of the heavy lifting off the development side,
making Hugo an enjoyable tool to work with.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-hugo">Why Hugo?
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>After working with HTML/CSS directly, transitioning to Hugo felt like
a leap forward in productivity. Here’s what stood out about Hugo that made
it a perfect fit for my needs:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Speed&lt;/strong>: Hugo is known for being incredibly fast at generating static
sites. Its speed is particularly helpful for managing multiple pages
without the lag you’d experience with other generators.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Flexibility&lt;/strong>: The support for SCSS and custom themes means I can
tweak every detail to fit my style and functional needs. The CaiJimmy
starter theme, in particular, includes various customization options,
so I can still enjoy designing without reinventing the wheel.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Content Management&lt;/strong>: Hugo organizes content through a structured
file system, making it easier to add, update, and organize posts and
pages. Unlike raw HTML/CSS, Hugo’s templating system and front matter
allow me to focus on content creation without duplicating the structure
of every new page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Shortcodes and Markdown Integration&lt;/strong>: Writing in Markdown allows for
faster content production, while Hugo’s shortcodes let me add rich
media, like videos and images, with a single line of code. It’s the
best of both worlds: simplicity for content creation and versatility
for interactivity.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="moving-forward-with-hugo">Moving Forward with Hugo
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Using Hugo has not only simplified my workflow but also introduced me to
new design possibilities. The Hugo community is vibrant and full of
resources, making it easy to find additional themes, tips, and tricks. I’m
excited to see how this tool can continue to support and evolve my
projects. Plus, now that I have this foundation, scaling the site will be
simpler, whether I want to add new sections, experiment with layouts, or
incorporate more interactive elements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For anyone on the fence about static site generators, especially if you’re
used to coding each element by hand, I can’t recommend Hugo enough. It
gives you all the customization of a hand-coded site without the
repetitive work. With the power of themes like CaiJimmy’s Hugo Theme
Starter, building and maintaining a website becomes less of a chore and
more of an enjoyable, creative process.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>