<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Yapping on Nishimiya</title><link>https://blog.nishimiya.my.id/categories/yapping/</link><description>Recent content in Yapping on Nishimiya</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.nishimiya.my.id/categories/yapping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Happy New Year! And My Plan for 2025</title><link>https://blog.nishimiya.my.id/post/happy-new-year-and-my-plan-for-2025/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:35:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nishimiya.my.id/post/happy-new-year-and-my-plan-for-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>As we step into 2025, I find myself reflecting on the journey that brought
me here. Looking back on 2024, it was a year filled with challenges and
growth. Life wasn’t always easy—managing unpaid debt and juggling daily
expenses made it tough—but it also had its moments of progress and
gratitude.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the most pivotal experiences was starting an internship in August.
At first, I didn’t expect to get paid, so when we were told midway through
the month that salaries would be provided, it felt like a lifeline. While
the income didn’t fully cover my college fee installments, it eased some
of the pressure, and for that, I’m incredibly thankful. By the end of the
three-and-a-half-month internship, we were given the option to continue
working there or explore new opportunities. I decided to stay, knowing
that even though the pay remained the same, it would help me chip away at
my financial challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reflecting on this, I’m reminded of another tough but transformative year:
2017. That year taught me the value of resilience and productivity. I was
trying to adjust to balancing school and life, all while indulging in
hobbies like tinkering with Linux and learning how to build websites. It
was one of my most frustrating periods because I felt like I was being
pulled in so many directions. But amid the chaos, I discovered the power
of structured planning. Inspired by Thomas Frank, a YouTube creator and
productivity expert, I started using a calendar to schedule my tasks. That
simple habit helped me bring order to the chaos and achieve a level of
productivity I hadn’t thought possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lessons I learned in 2017 have stayed with me. I’ve realized that
sometimes, the hardest years are the ones that push us to grow the most.
Now, as I look to 2025, I want to carry forward that same spirit of
resilience and productivity to tackle my goals head-on.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="my-plans-for-2025">My Plans for 2025
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In 2025, I want to focus on four main areas of my life:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Graduate from College with No Debt&lt;/strong>
My top priority is to finish college on time and debt-free. Clearing my college
dues is a big challenge, but I’m determined to make it happen by working hard,
budgeting wisely, and staying disciplined.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Return to Calendar-Based Task Planning&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Just like I did in 2017, I want to bring back the habit of scheduling my tasks
on a calendar. That year taught me how powerful structured planning can be. By
organizing my time, I was able to balance school, hobbies, and personal
projects—even during the toughest periods. I’m hoping to recreate that level of
focus and discipline in 2025.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pursue Tech Projects&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Get an Orange Pi Zero&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
I’ve been dreaming about getting an Orange Pi Zero to set up a tiny MPD
server or even experiment with Jellyfin (though I know it might be too
demanding). My goal is to save enough to buy it by mid-2025. Until then,
I’ll keep using my laptop to host my MPD radio station whenever it’s on.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Host My Own Website&lt;/strong>
Hosting my own website has been a long-standing dream. I’ve explored
platforms like Render.com and Netlify, but they come with their own hurdles.
For now, I’ll stick to using GitHub Pages while I figure out how to overcome
these challenges, like setting environment variables on Netlify or renewing
my debit card for Render.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Build IoT Projects for My Home&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
I’ve always wanted to create IoT projects to make life at home more
efficient and fun. Budget permitting, I plan to dive into these projects in
2025 and maybe even share my experiences in future blog posts.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Write My Thesis&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Starting in January, I’ll begin writing my thesis. It’s a daunting task, but
I’m ready to approach it with determination and gratitude.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>